Welcome back to AM Northwest. If
your family heirlooms are starting to
accumulate, how do you know which ones
are really worth keeping? Here to share
some helpful tips, we welcome back antique
appraiser Gary Germer. Great to see
you, Gary. >> You too, Helen. Thank you.
>> Okay, you I bet you you have a lot
of great collections.
Personally, I don't. I'm I'm kind of a
minimalist. No way. >> think it's because
I'm around it all day long. And so I
it's kind of like I owned it while it was
Yeah. >> And then >> excited about certain
things. >> Oh, I love it all. I get
I'm like a child in this. That's why
I've had I tell people I probably would
have made more money if I'd gone into
real estate, but I wouldn't have any fun.
>> There you go. Okay, let's start
with a couple of these. These are like
holiday items. Here is like a pumpkin.
Right. Well, I know we last time I was
here we talked some about holiday things.
And this is What I did is I to prep
for this, I called several friends of
mine who are weekend warriors who go out
every weekend to buy things. >> Yeah.
What do they make the most money on?
Holiday things. People give them away
for nothing. And these can be worth
significant money. Um This is definitely
an antique. >> Yeah, these are these
are really kind of fun. And obviously
we had in So there's other stuff that
isn't quite as neat. But if you're
looking at stuff from say the 1960s and
earlier Yeah. Uh chances are it's
worth significant money. And so
>> where do you sell it? Well, there are
all all sorts of places for collectors
to look for things like this, right? >>
Right. And I I have some lists that I I
gave to Cammy, the producer. And we're
going to have them up online for people
to to connect with. But if you're going
to research the values on stuff, it look
get familiar with eBay advanced search.
And look for what sold. Don't just skim
through eBay cuz people ask crazy prices
for stuff. >> Yeah. And if it's sold,
you can see what it actually sold
for. Holiday things are people will be
cleaning out grandma's house. And oh,
that's kind of cool. They keep a few
things. And then oops. Then they end up
just breaking and you know, just blowing
them out for nothing. Okay. >> can do
really well. >> the like the Santa, too.
>> Any fun. Yeah. Okay. One of the
things that caught me because I'm getting
ancient here is up front are video games.
Um my kids' generation, they're they're
in their late 30s, my two daughters. Uh
can be worth significant money. Really?
>> Used video games. So you have like
the two here I brought about four, but
the the little cartridges here that
aren't in the box are still 40 bucks.
>> Oh. This one here is 50. This Pokémon
one is $250.
Oh, wow. >> from And so the record
world record for it is for an original
um Mario Brothers >> Mhm. the original
cartridge in its original packaging,
never opened sold in at Heritage Auctions
in Texas last year for $1.6 million.
No way. Wow. Incredible. >> the What
it is is people tend to buy their
childhood. >> Yes. I was going to say
that's the age that you're looking at now.
That makes sense. >> Exactly. And that's
why if you're cleaning out the house,
the kids have been out of the house for
20, 30 years, and you're going to get
rid of all of their toys
and stuff that's accumulated
slow down, check into it. >> And see
what you can sell. >> There's a place
called um
Loo- Lucky Shop.com.
Again, this will be on the website >>
Okay. uh of where we'll help you to
research whether or not you have anything
really good. >> Okay. You have books,
too. >> Books. Now, of course, the
number one way that you get money out of
books is by shaking them.
>> [laughter] >> Yeah. So if you're
cleaning grandma's house, make sure you can
like take a minute and look through the
books. >> Children's books have held
their value. A lot of interest in children's
books and cookbooks. And people can
make a living just with that. If they're
in But condition, condition, condition.
But there's people who collect like the
Alticott winners like this one here.
They'll collect all the Alticott
winners. So Again, it's going back to the
childhood. Childhood. >> Right. Yeah,
and and and uh And of course, a lot of
books are valuable, we know. But the
ABEBooks is a great place to research
those. >> And And this one I've never
heard of before. Well, the reason that
this is interesting is it's is the
illustrator is Maurice Sendak. Where the Wild
Things Are. >> So he was a great illustrator
of a lot of different books. This
is kind of a rare one that he illustrated
that you don't see very often. And so
it's a dumb story, I think. That's why
it never sold. But [laughter] But the
illustrations were amazing. >> worth
records. I know we've had records on
before.
People constantly make a living with
records cuz they go to garage sales and buy
them for your choice, $1, $2 each.
You know. And then they take them and
they sell them anywhere from 10 to $20.
And sometimes they score big. And but
you can consistently get a lot more money
from your records if you take some time,
especially if they're rock and roll.
That nobody really wants the the Percy
Faith and the stuff that our parents
listen to. You know, the easy listening
stuff. But the stuff like um you know,
rock and roll and jazz and things like
that. If you had a record collection and
it's has gathered dust for the last 30
years, take your time, do some homework.
Discogs.com
is the place to do your research. >> Okay,
great. Okay, somebody clearly knows a
drag queen. >> Yes, yes. >> this so much,
so much. >> one that fits me with the
with the with the glasses. >> Look
at that. >> Mask. That's incredible.
[laughter] Wow. >> And I've been told
that I have a flair for the obvious, but
it is obvious that you're going to look
at your jewelry. Yeah. >> But I have a
friend of mine who goes every weekend to
estate sales and garage sales. And last
year she told me she made 24
thousand dollars by picking gold and
silver out of a box just like this that
said your choice $3 each or $2 each.
Because she can tell the difference between
gold and silver. >> keeps a you you So
if you're if you're going to take time,
really look at it. It'll be marked 14K,
18K. Learn your marks and really look at
it. Then there's other things like this
is a designer piece. >> That's made by
Yves Saint Laurent. And so if it was
just a regular checklist of auction set,
you'd be looking at maybe a hundred bucks.
But because it's a a um runway piece
with Yves Saint Laurent, you're looking
at Are you saying these are real
diamonds? I wish. I wouldn't be here.
>> can't be right. >> be in Hawaii now,
but >> Okay. >> [laughter] >> But it's
But it's the designer that makes it
expensive. >> what you want to
look for is what they call branded.
Branded jewelry. Um uh and you know,
they they all did it. Chanel I mean,
designed some. Yves, you know, all of
them did. A set like this uh it's between
five and seven hundred dollars. >> that
so much. >> Yeah. And then this uh mask
>> was one that came from uh um you know,
Spencer's Gifts. You know. It's just a
fun little rain storm. And it'll bring
you 20 bucks, you know. But that's the
That's the thing about it is that you
need to slow down and take your time with
a jewelry box. There's more money per
square foot here usually than anything
else you're dealing with. >> Oh, okay.
People think, oh, it's one item. Vintage
clothes, everybody knows vintage clothes
still hot. I still have clients who
we're we're going to be running in a
estate sale for them. Oh, honey, we helped
you. We gave grandma's clothes away
already before we got here. And I want to
just
you know, No. >> No. You [laughter] want
to keep the clothes. Okay. >> So check
the vintage clothes. And condition again
means everything. But it's a re- still
a red hot market. >> Yeah. So if you're
thinning things out, look at it that
way. Okay. And what do you have in a uh
an old >> I have my old Bose radio here.
And the reason I brought that is another
major thing that that is hot is old
electronics. Okay. And you can you can
uh if especially if you have stereos that
have tubes Uh-huh. you know, old ones
that are working condition or whatnot uh
can be surprisingly valuable. Bose,
anything Bose or brand name like that um
it's one of the top things that sell on
eBay and the internet is is old I don't
know why, but old electronics. And some
of the old like tube receivers and stuff
have a much better sound or whatnot. So
if you have a stereo, I haven't played a
record in 30 years and it's been in the
you know, sat there. Before you just
haul it off to Goodwill >> Yeah.
there's a website called AudioGone.
And again, we'll be on site. >> Yeah. Uh
that will you it's a it's where it buys
and sells it. So I'm buy
and sell electronics.
And you can get exactly where the market's
at on that sort of stuff. >> Who knew
about that? That's fascinating. Gary >>
Yeah. great advice. >> Yeah. Thank you,
sir, very much. I love this. I love this
especially. All right, we're going to
put that information, as Gary said, on
our website at katu.com. All right, we'll